Manuel E. Gondra Manuscript Collection:
Calendar of the Manuel E. Gondra Manuscript Collection, The University of Texas Library, prepared by Carlos Eduardo Castañeda, University of Texas, and Jack Autrey Dabbs, AM College of Texas. México: Editorial Jus, 1952.
- Eighteenth Century Documents (1778-1799)
  - 2169 PARAGUAY, REAL HACIENDA DEL. Puntos que proponen [al comandante de Puertos y Conducción]... para la provicion de viveres por asiento a las guarniciones de los fuertes de Borbón y San Carlos de Río Apá. Asunción, August 27, 1799. 2 p. 22 × 33 cm. p. 5-6. Modern copy from V. 27-32-49, with du
    Signed: Martín José de Aramburu, and Juan José González. Includes order of Lázaro de Rivera, September 9, 1799, forwarding the proposal to the Real Hacienda.
  - 2170 _____. Acuerdo de Real Hacienda [aprobando los puntos propuestos para la provisión de víveres a los fuertes de Borbón y San Carlos.] Asunción, September 20, 1799. 2 p. 22 × 33 cm. p. 11-13. Modern copy from V. 27-32-49. (Box [MG 2009c])
    Signed: Lázaro de Rivera, Tomás González, Martín José de Aramburu, Juan José González, and Marcos Ignacio Baldovinos. Includes certificates of promulgation by José Antonio Balderrain, Concepción? September? 27, 1799 and October 19, 1799, the order of Rivera, September 27, 1799, for auction in Asunción.
  - 2171 Zavala y Delgadillo, José Antonio de. Liquidación de rentas de Vengada por el Doctor Zavala Delgadillo, catedrático de Teología y filosofía en el Colegio de San Carlos 1798. [Certificación de los herederos del canónigo Juan Antonio de Zavala y Delgadillo sobre haber partido los bienes de éste.] Asunción, October 1, 1799. 2 l. 21 × 25 cm. f. 1-2. Original, deteriorated condition. (Box [MG 1973a])
    Also signed by María Josefa and María Ana Zavala y Delgadillo.
  - 2172 Rivera, Lázaro de. [Carta a Miguel Cayetano Soler en que se queja de las persecuciones que le hace el Virrey de Buenos Aires.] Asunción, October 21, 1799. 17 l. 17 × 23 cm. Modern copy from AGI 124-1-7-B. (Box [MG 1698])
    Plan for dividing Guaraní missions; donations; excessive tax on Indian industries.
  - 2173 CONSEJO DE INDIAS. [Oficio a S. M. sobre la cuestión de construcción de bajeles en el Paraguay.] Madrid, 1799? 24 l. 17 × 23 cm. Modern copy from AGI 124-1-5-E. (Box [MG 1696])
    Letter of Miguel Cayetano Soler to the Consejo; stimulation of trade with river boats; commission of Tomás Ortega Fernández and Casimiro Francisco de Nechochea, Juan Machaín, José Astigarribia, and Sebastián de Aramburu; royal regulation on use of ships built outside of Spain; opinions of Diego de Alvear and Félix Azara requested.
  - 2174 NOTAS DEL MINISTERIO DE ESTADO / NOTAS DELA ACADEMIA DE LA HISTORIA / APUNTES SOBRE LIMITES CON BOLIVIA, BRASIL Y REP. ARG. 1784-1799., 10. l. 22 × 30 cm. (Box [MG 1978])
    Geographical material and bibliographical notes on boundary questions.